好啊 胡安!
Hey, Juan!
- 早啊 胡安! - 早啊 胡安
- Morning, Juan! - Morning, Juan.
嗨 胡安!
Hi, Juan!
好啊 胡安!
Hello, Juan!
这周六又可以看见他了
Another Saturday he returns.
喔 宝贝
Whoo, baby.
问候胡安 我们亲爱的园丁
Greetings, Juan the garden maker,
带来鲜花 带走杂草
bringer of flowers, cutter of grass.
马克斯 你的汉堡好了
Max, your burger's ready when you are.
不吃了 谢谢 胡安要教我怎么除草
Oh, no, thanks. Juan's gonna teach me how to mow!
他很喜欢胡安
He loves Juan.
胡安确实不错
Oh, Juan's the best.
拉里 说实话
I'm telling you, Larry,
你们外星人错过了很多好东西 伙计
you aliens are missing out, man.
吃培根芝士汉堡是人生的一大享受
The bacon cheeseburger is one of the finest joys of life.
你们这些人类不过是穿着网球鞋的猴子
You humans are just monkeys in tennis shoes.
拉里 吃点东西又能怎样?
Larry, what would happen if you ate food?
我不知道
I have no idea.
察布隆人的身体极度敏感
Zabvronians' bodies are extremely sensitive.
怎么 你害怕吗?
What are you, afraid?
- 你真的是害怕啊 - 噢 马蒂
- You're afraid. - Oh! Marty...
我可是高级生命体
I am a higher life form.
- 激将法对我没用 - 拉里害怕了 拉里害怕了
- Taunts and threats have no effect on me. - Larry's afraid. Larry's afraid.
- 拉里是个... - 吃就吃!
- Larry's a... - Give it here!
我不喜欢
No, I don't like it.
跑得真爽
Great run!
我还是不明白我们为什么要跑步
I still don't understand why we did it.
为了好看
To look good!
但是你现在难看极了 是我见过的最丑的一次
But you look terrible, like the worst I've ever seen.
好吧 谢谢你这么说
Okay. Thanks for that.
不喝?
No?
知道吗?
Oh... You know what?
我觉得我该去冲个澡
I think I'm gonna take a bath.
没有比脱掉所有的衣服
There's nothing like stripping down
好好泡个热水澡更惬意的事情了
to what you were born with and having a good, hot soak.
肌肉也可以放松放松
It really relaxes the muscles.
我的肌肉一点都不酸
Well, my muscles are not sore.
你假装一下能死吗?
Would it kill you to act like they were?
我知道 很酸是不是?
I know, right?
脱掉所有衣服
Stripping down to what I was born with.
夫人!
Wife!
马蒂・韦弗逼我吃了一头牛!
Marty Weaver made me eat a cow!
夫人!我需要听众!
Wife! I demand an audience!
我在楼上 拉里・伯德!
I'm upstairs, Larry Bird!
哦 嗯 胡安?
Oh. Uh, Juan?
等你在地上一动不动躺够了
When you're done lying motionless on the ground,
你能到绕到前面
perhaps you could come round the front
给那些灌木浇点水吗 它们有点干了
and water the shrubbery. It's a bit dry.
胡安?
Juan?
我叫救护车了 他们马上到
I called 9-1-1. They're on their way.
好的 伙计们 这到底怎么回事?
Good. Now what the hell, guys?
这也太诡异了!
This is really weird!
我也这么想 是吧?我们想叫醒他
I know, right? We tried to get his attention,
但是我们不会西班牙语
but we don't speak spanish.
我的天啊 不要碰他!
Oh, my god, don't touch the body!
一定不能碰他的身体!
You never touch the body!
我觉得这话已经说晚了
Well, I think it's a little late for that.
伙计们 胡安不是不理你们
Guys, Juan isn't ignoring you.
他只是...你懂得
He's... You know.
死了
Dead.
- 死了? - 是的 死了
- Dead? - Dead.
- 没错死了 - 那就让他别死了
- Dead. - Well, make him stop.
- 我们做不到 - 为什么做不到?
- We can't. - Why not?
好了 知道吗?
Okay, you know what?
马蒂 孩子们随时有可能进来!
Marty, the kids could come in any second!
而我们沙发上坐着个死人
We have a dead man on our sofa!
他不能待在这!对不起 胡安
He can't stay! I'm sorry, Juan.
可怜的胡安 但是他必须走!
Oh, poor Juan. He's gotta go!
稍等一下 我觉得这挺有意思的
Hold on a second, 'cause I find this fascinating.
你们不知道死亡是什么?
Do you guys not know what death is?
我们当然知道 自从变成人类
Of course we do. Since taking human form,
我们每天晚上死六个小时
we die every night for six hours.
个人觉得八个小时更好
Preferably eight.
然后到了早上 我们再活过来 神清气爽
And in the morning, we un-die, refreshed.
有时候跟杰西爱爱之后我也会死一会儿
Sometimes I die after mating with Jackie.
我是在做的时候死
I die during.
我明白了
I see.
那是睡觉啊!你们说的是睡觉啊!
Sleep! You're talking about sleep!
而这是死亡 是生命的终结!
This is death, the end of life!
杰西 不要再动胡安!
Jackie, stop touching Juan!
好吧 听好了 伙计们
Okay... Listen up, guys.
对于人类来说 死亡就是终结!
For humans, death is it the end!
就好像灯泡烧坏了再也不会亮了
It's like a light burning out that never comes back!
嗨 伙计们 哦 嗨 胡安
Hey, guys. Oh, hey, Juan.
谢谢让我玩你的车
Thanks for letting me ride in your cart.
小意思!
No problemo!
哦 我的天啊!
Oh, my god!
没错 我就是那么做的
Yep, I did that.
胡安 再见
Good-bye, Juan.
真不知道我们挥什么手 他又看不见
I don't know why we're waving. He can't see us.
因为难受 他是那么好的一个人
Because it's sad. He was a sweet man.
没错 他确实是
Yeah, he was.
看来我们得回去告诉马克斯这个坏消息了
Guess we should go break the news to Max.
哦 我也不想
Ohh, I don't want to, either.
但是马克斯喜欢胡安
But Max loved Juan.
你知道 他们总是在一起
You know, they spent a lot of time together.
胡安让他帮忙浇水
Juan let him help with the watering,
除草 清理除草机
pulling the weeds, emptying the mower bag.
你就没想过胡安是拿咱儿子当免费劳动力呢?
You ever think Juan might have been using our son for free labor?
马蒂 这是件很严肃的事儿 好吗?
Marty, this is a big deal, okay?
我是说 马克斯知道死亡是什么
I mean, Max knows about death,
但是他还从没有失去过这么亲近的人
but he's never had anyone close to him pass away.
他的爷爷奶奶都健在 也从没有死过宠物
He has all of his grandparents. He's never lost a pet.
我是说 至少他自己不知道
I mean, not one that he knows of.
是啊 那次我们火速把死掉的寄居蟹换走了
Yeah, we did pull off that impressive hermit crab switcheroo.
稍等一下 你认为我们可不可能...
Wait a minute. Do you think that we could possibly...
- 马蒂 - 没错 这不是什么好主意
- Marty. - Right. That's a bad idea.
好的 我们可以做到的 你知道?
Okay, we can do this, you know?
我们坐下来 和他好好谈谈
We'll just sit him down, have a conversation like we did
把他当成杰西・乔伊娜・柯西和拉里・伯德
with Jackie Joyner-Kersee and Larry Bird.
我们和他们谈的不错 不是吗?
That went well, right?
是的
Yeah.
大限将近
啊 你们来了
Ah, there you are.
拉里 这到底是怎么回事?
Larry, what the hell is going on?
我跟他们解释了下死亡是什么
Oh, I explained death to the community,
然后他们问及死亡发生的具体时间
and they asked specifically when it happens,
而我不得不向他们承认我不知道
and I had to confess that I did not know,
由此引发了小小的恐慌
and it caused a bit of a panic.
也许你们可以解释一下?
Maybe you can clear things up?
不过我们需要和马克斯先谈谈
Well, actually, we need to talk to Max.
好极了 同志们
Excellent. Community.
集合
Your attention!
马蒂・韦弗将向大家解释死亡是如何
Marty Weaver will now explain how death comes...
在一个预先设置好的时间
At a prearranged moment,
当你在身体上和精神上都准备好时发生的
when you're physically and mentally prepared,
而且合情合理 公平且毫无痛苦
and it's always reasonable, fair, and painless.
马蒂
Marty.
好吧 实际上是这样的
Okay, here's the thing.
它不会在预先设置好的时间发生 好吗?
It's doesn't come at a prearranged moment, okay?
你也不会准备好
And you're never prepared,
而且死亡也不是什么毫无痛苦的
and it is never painless.
也许你可以回答几个问题
Maybe you could answer some questions.
好吧 没问题
Yeah, okay, fine.
但是就几个 你 印度人
But just a couple. Uh, you, the indian one?
我们都会死吗?
Are we going to die?
我不知道
I don't know.
左面第三个 裤子提到胸口的那位?
The third from left, the pants too high?
既然知道你会死 你还活什么啊?
How do you go on, Knowing you're going to die?
活着还有什么意义?
What's the point?
活着的意义在于不去考虑死亡
The point is to enjoy life while you can
尽可能的享受生活
and not think about when it's going to end.
我们称之为否认
It's called denial.
就你 前面那个 矮个子双性人
You... up front, little man-woman?
什么是否认?
What is this denial?
就是让自己忙个不停
Well, it's keeping yourself busy,
还有其他的消遣 比如 美食 购物 啤酒
distractions... you know, food, shopping, alcohol,
这样你就不用考虑这种事了
So you don't have to think about things.
没错没错 拿我来说
Yeah, yeah, take me, for instance, okay?
我家里一半的人都有心脏病
Over half my family had heart attacks.
- 我想过这事儿吗? - 一次都没有!
- Does that ever cross my mind? - Not once!
相反的是 他上网打扑克 经常吃芝士汉堡
Instead, he plays computer poker and eats cheeseburgers
从没想过要戒掉
with reckless abandon.
没错 我的心脏状况很不好
Yeah, my heart's so bad,
实际上它跳动的时候跟哨子里的小珠子似的
it practically whistles when it beats.
真的吗?
It does?
我只是想让他们安心
Well, I just want to put their mind at ease.
- 配合我一下就行 - 哦 好的
- So just go with me. - Oh. Okay.
说实话 我的意思是如果像这样继续吃下去
I mean, honestly, if I keep stuffing my face like this,
五年之后我还在这的话就是奇迹了
it'll be a miracle if I'm even around in five years.
所以你看 说白了 我是个活死人
Look, basically, I'm a dead man walking,
但我觉得这没什么
and I'm okay with it.
他觉得这没什么
And he's okay with it.
我会死
I'm gonna die.
多大点事儿啊
Big whoop.
你要死了?!
You're gonna die?!
马克斯 我们本打算和你谈谈这事儿的
Oh, Max, we were going to talk to you about this.
不是关于你爸 而是胡安
Not about daddy, about Juan.
胡安出事了?
There's something wrong with Juan?
嗯...
Well, um...
哦 我的天啊!
Oh, my gosh!
马克斯!
Max!
我真不敢相信胡安死了
I can't believe Juan died.
我不希望爸爸也死了
I don't want daddy to die, too.
亲爱的 不会的
Honey, that is not going to happen.
是的 我说我有哨子心
Yeah, I only said I had a whistling heart
只是想让那些外星人好受点
to make the aliens feel better.
但是胡安死了
But Juan died.
没错 但是胡安已经很老了
That's true, but Juan was very old.
他都...
He was...
- 黛比 他多大了? - 四十五岁
- Debbie, how old was he? - 45.
四十五?!老天爷啊
45?! Oh, my god,
他太阳底下呆太久了
He spent a lot of time in the sun.
只有老人会死吗?
Only old people die?
- 不 - 是的
- No. - Yes.
- 是的 - 不
- Yes. - No.
如果你们死了 就剩我一个人了
But if you guys die, i'll be all alone.
嗨 如果我向你保证
Hey, what if I promised you
我们都会一起死呢?
that we all die at exactly the same time?
你会觉得好受点吗 儿子?
Would that make you feel better, sport?
你脑子进水了吗?
Are you nuts?
我怎么会觉得好受呢?
How would that make me feel better?
你刚刚是在让自己的儿子选择自杀还是被杀吗?
Did you just promise our son a murder/suicide pact?
我后悔了
I'm regretting the choice.
宝贝 你不需要为这些事担心
Honey, you don't have to worry about any of this.
没有人会死
Nobody's going to die.
你们都会死的
You're all going to die.
你们发什么神经?我们儿子被你们吓死了
What the hell was that? We got a freaked-out kid in there.
很抱歉打扰你们
So sorry to bother you,
但是我们是来谈谈一些善后事宜的
but we've come to terms with your eventual demise,
我们在此道别
and we are here to say farewell.
非常感谢 杰西 但是你有点反应过度了
Appreciate that, Jackie, But you're being a little ridiculous.
我反应过度?
We are being ridiculous?
你们才是向死亡妥协的人
You're the ones that are so accepting of death!
抗争啊!解决问题啊!
Fight it! Solve the problem!
我一生都在解决问题
I've been a problem solver my entire life.
我玩西洋棋很厉害 还很擅长俄罗斯方块
I'm great at checkers. I own tetris.
这不过是数学而已
It's simple math.
你们可以活下去 你们却要死
You're capable of being alive. You die.
你们应该可以再活一次
You should be capable of being alive again.
这个问题无解
It's not a solvable problem.
事实是我们对于胡安的离世
The fact is that we were all rather taken by surprise
感到万分的震惊
by Juan's passing.
我们不希望这样的事再发生
We don't want that to happen again,
所以我们必须保护自己免受伤害
so we must protect ourselves from future hurt.
所以我们想和那些不会死去的东西做朋友
So we're thinking of becoming friends with things that don't die,
比如金鱼 狗啊
Like goldfish or dogs.
你们在来地球前做过调查吗?
Did you guys do any research before you came to this planet?
我只是好奇而已
I'm just wondering.
知道吗 我有个想法
You know what? I got an idea.
马蒂 你知道胡安的葬礼在哪举行吗?
Marty, do you know where they're having Juan's funeral?
是的 因为我脑子里有本葬礼信息查询表
Yes, because I have a direct feed of all funeral information that goes right into my head.
哦 好了 哨子心
Ah! Okay, you know what, heart whistle?
别再用这词儿了 好吗?
Let's lose the smart-ass remarks, okay?
这是件好事
It'll be a good thing.
他们需要理解所发生的事情
They need to process what has happened.
而且不仅仅是他们
And they're not the only ones.
告诉我
Tell me something...
你既然知道俄罗斯方块 怎么会不知道死亡呢?
How do you know about tetris, but you don't know about death?
殡仪馆 萨尔加多葬礼十点举行
好了 在我们进去之前
All right, now before we go in,
切记 这是一个悲伤肃穆的仪式 好吗?
remember, this is a somber event, okay?
- 因此几条规矩 - 问个问题!
- So a few ground rules... - A question!
- 为什么我们要穿成这样?
Why are we dressed like this?
我不知道 我特别告诉拉里
I don't know. I specifically told larry
不要穿成这样 他却固执己见
not to dress that way. He insisted.
有人告诉我这是为了庆祝胡安一生的庆典
I was told this was a celebration of Juan's life.
我们察布隆人总是衣着得体的参加庆典
We Zabvronians always dress appropriately for a celebration.
好吧好吧 是我的错
Okay, well, yeah, my bad.
我确实说过是"生命的庆典"
I did use the term "celebration of life."
但我不是说夏威夷烤猪宴
I did not mean a luau.
我觉得自己傻到家了
Well, I fell silly.
但是也没问题 说明你们关心在意
But okay, you know, it shows that you care,
这也就是葬礼的意义所在
and that's what this is about...
给认识胡安的人一个机会
Giving the people who knew Juan
告诉大家胡安对他们来说有多重要
an opportunity to express how important he was to them,
同时也让这些人知道即使胡安已经去世了
and then letting those people know that even though Juan is gone,
他也会永远活在他们心中
he will live in their hearts forever.
那些心里会永远记着胡安的人都哪去了?
So where are all these people In whose hearts Juan will live forever?
不好意思
Excuse me.
我们来早了吗?其余的人哪去了?
Do we have the wrong time? Where is everyone?
萨尔加多先生的妻子几年前就过世了
Mr. Salgado's wife passed several years ago,
他唯一的亲人是住在新不伦瑞克省的表弟
and his only family is a cousin who lives in new brunswick
位于加拿大 毗邻美国
但是他无法前来
But couldn't make the trip.
新不伦瑞克?
New Brunswick?
离这好像也就一小时的路程吧
That's, like, an hour away.
他们平时不怎么往来
They weren't close.
胡安的离开让我们意识到生命是多么的短暂
Juan's death reminds us how short life is.
也让我们意识到眼下的时光是多么宝贵
But it also reminds us how precious every moment can be...
来说说那个木船是什么玩意
So tell me about the wooden boat.
那不是船 是棺材 胡安的遗体躺在里面
It's not a boat. It's a coffin. It's where Juan's body is buried.
也就是说仪式结束要把船带去湖里漂走咯
And is part of the ceremony taking the boat to a lake to sail it about?
再声明一下 那不是船
Again, not a boat.
这个其实是要埋到地下去的
It actually gets buried in the ground.
也就是说你们埋葬你们深爱的人
So you bury the people you love,
却把一个填满材料的麋鹿头挂在墙上?
but a moose you just met you stuff and mount on a wall?
他说的有道理
He makes a good point.
现在请认识胡安的人和我们分享一下
This is a good time for anyone who knew Juan
对他的回忆
to share some words.
我想说几句
I'd like to say something.
胡安对我们意义非凡
Juan was important to us.
尽管我们认识他没多久
Although we did not know him for a long time,
他把我们的花园打理得漂漂亮亮
he kept our gardens beautiful,
对我们也很和善 我们会想念他的
and he was sweet to us, and we will miss him.
胡安是我们搬到这儿后最早遇到的人类之一
Juan was one of the first people we met when we moved here.
一开始我们以为他是和机器连在一起的
At first we thought he was attached to his machine,
类似于半人半割草机
sort of a half-man, half-mower.
他有一次碾过了我的脚
He once ran over my foot.
我疼死了!
Oh, yeah. It hurt!
不好意思 我刚才发觉在这里发光发热
I'm sorry, guys. I just feel that the energy expended here will be better spent
比费力解决死亡的问题好受多了
trying to solve this death thing.
这是献给你的 胡安
This is for you, Juan.
死亡再难也不会难过七级俄罗斯方块啊
It can't be harder than tetris level seven.
你在开玩笑吗?
Are you kidding me?
和飞机餐一起送来的是什么?
What is it with airplane food?
餐叉不会觉得尴尬吗?
Aren't forks weird?
胡安对我而言如父亲一般
Juan was like the father I never had.
- 啥? - 呃
- What? - Oh.
大家一起来为他献上一曲
Let us sing to him the song we all know.
我一直在铁路上工作
I've been working on the railroad
一生都是
all the live-long day
我一直在铁路上工作
I've been working on the railroad
只是为了打发时间
Just to pass the time away
马克斯 如果你觉得难过 这很正常
If you're sad, Max, it's okay.
男子汉可以哭
Men can cry.
你也知道你爹看大都会队比赛时是什么德行
You've seen daddy watch the mets.
谢谢你 黛比・韦弗
Thank you, Debbie Weaver.
你是对的 我们确实感觉好多了
You were right. We do feel better.
- 那你呢 小伙子?感觉好点了吗? - 嗯
- How about you, buddy? You feel better? - Yeah.
我是说 这虽然挺悲伤 但只要我记得他
I mean, it's sad, but as long as I can remember him,
即使见不到他也没什么关系
maybe it's okay I won't get to see him again.
诸位 好消息
Good news, everyone.
我知道如何战胜死亡了
I figured out how to beat death.
胡安归来
Juan has returned.
他让咱们的园丁起死回生了
He bought our gardener back from the dead.
不错 是我干的
Yes, I did.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你只需要知道拉里・伯德一比零战胜了死神
All you need to know is, Larry Bird 1, death 0.
我知道我抱怨过这鬼地方
I know I complain a lot about living in this cul-du-wack,
不过这确实是我见过的最奇妙的事情
but this is the greatest thing I've ever seen.
胡安到底是死是活?
Is Juan dead or alive?
- 死 - 活
- Dead. - Alive.
- 活 - 死
夫君 我不太确定我对此的感受
Husband, I'm not quite sure how I feel about this.
可能是我的原因 可是胡安看起来有点...
Maybe it's just me, but Juan seems a little bit...
不一样
Different.
才没呢 他现在焕然一新
No, no, he's as good as new.
真的?你这么觉得?
Really? Is that what you think?
如果把这事传到Facebook上会怎样?
What's our policy on facebooking this?
嘿 大家都在看什么呐?
Hey, what's everyone looking at?
看瓢虫!
A ladybug!
我能看看吗?
Can I see?
不能!它飞走了!
No! Flew away!
琥珀 我知道你想和艾比一起玩洋娃娃
Amber, I know you want to play dollies with Abby,
你妈不是在征求意见 而是命令你
your mother says, not asking, but commanding.
没错 既然有洋娃娃玩
Ah, yes. Why bear witness to a resurrection
我们还管什么起死回生的神迹啊?
when there are dolls to be played with?
拉里 你到底对他做了什么?
Larry, what the hell did you do to him?
这有什么关系?反正他复活了
What does it matter? He's back.
我还以为人死后你就再也见不到他了
I thought when someone died, you never saw them again.
- 先等等 马克斯 - 我不懂了
- Hold on a second, Max. - I'm confused.
宝贝 爸爸妈妈要先解决一些问题
Honey, mommy and daddy are trying to fix something.
- 已经解决了! - 来个人回答我啊!
- Fixed it! - Somebody answer me!
这事违反自然规律的 拉里
This is not natural, Larry.
你吃的大部分食物也不合自然规律
Well, neither is most of the food that you eat,
- 可你不还是挺享受的 - 他说得有道理
- but you seem to enjoy that. - He's got a point.
别把我吃什么扯进来!
Don't bring my food into this!
你的饮食习惯和野兽没啥区别
You eat like an animal.
嘿 胡安
Hey, Juan.
我有好多事情不懂
I'm confused about a bunch of things.
你能回答我几个问题吗?
Will you answer some questions?
你死了吗?你见到上帝了吗?
Are you dead? Did you meet god?
你去过天堂了吗?
Did you go to heaven?
会不会很疼?那里黑吗?
Did it hurt? Was it dark?
你有没有见到我的寄居蟹?
Did you see my hermit crab?
我爸妈说就是现在的那只
My parents say it's the same one,
不过我深表怀疑
but I'm suspicious.
大家都死了吗?
Does everyone die?
还是说没有人死?你死了
Does no one die? You died.
我爸爸也快死了吗?
Is my dad going to die?
拉里 我知道现在气氛很紧张
Okay, Larry, I know tempers are high,
但是你不能说我丈夫是猪脑子
but it is not appropriate to call my husband a poopy-head.
- 他本来就是 - 我才不是
- Well, he is. - I am not.
- 傻子说傻话 - 拉里 你必须把胡安弄回他应有的状态
- Are, too. - Larry, you have to put Juan back the way he was.
我已经解决了死亡这个难题
Look, I have solved the problem of death.
- 接受我的大礼吧 - 拉里・伯德 你必须告诉我们真相
- Accept it as a gift. - Larry Bird, you need to tell them the truth.
- 真相是什么? - 真相是你老公是猪脑子
- What is the truth? - That your husband is a poopy-head.
拉里・赫伯特・沃克尔・伯德!
Larry Herbert Walker Bird!
他什么也没有解决 他都不知道自己是怎么做到的
He hasn't solved anything. He doesn't even know how he did it.
我知道!
I do know how I did it!
只是再也做不了了而已
I just can't do it again.
拉里 你们在说什么?
Larry, what are you talking about?
在我来这个星球之前 我父亲给了我一小瓶药
Before I came to this planet, my father gave me one vial of medicine,
他告诉我 除非万不得已 否则不能喝它
and he told me, should the worst happen, only then should I use it.
当时我不懂他什么意思 但是胡安一死我就明白了
And I didn't know what he was talking about until Juan died.
拉里 你只有一瓶药 而你把它给了胡安?
Larry, you only had one, and you used it on Juan?
- 你把它用给了胡安? - 事情就这样发生了
- You used it on Juan? - It just happened!
我当时...站在胡安的棺材船旁边
I was... standing next to Juan's coffin boat...
- 再说一次 不是船 - 先别纠正
- Again, not a boat. - Not the time.
有种难以名状的感觉淹没了我
And this indescribable wave of emotion came over me, and...
哦 拉里 这叫悲伤
Oh, Larry, it's called sadness.
这很正常
It's natural.
不过接下来的事就不叫正常了
Just what came after was not.
不 不是悲伤
No, I didn't feel sad.
我觉得很无力
I felt powerless.
对
Yes.
我 伟大的拉里・伯德
I, the great Larry Bird,
感到无力
powerless.
你们没什么反应?
Really? Nothing?
- 无力啊 - 我被吓呆了 难以置信
- Powerless, yeah. - Shocking. I can't believe it. Wow.
问题在于
The thing is,
我和我夫君还不是很懂人类身体怎样运作
my husband and I still don't quite understand how these bodies work.
自从变成人类 我们也得睡觉
Since taking human form, we now sleep.
要是我们也...死了怎么办?
What if we now also... die?
好吧
Okay.
打扰一下 年幼的马克斯・韦弗正坐在你家屋顶上
Excuse me. Young Max Weaver is sitting on your roof.
什么?
What?
马克斯 你在上面做什么?!
Max, what are you doing up there?!
没人愿意和我说话
Nobody will talk to me.
我很迷惑 我有好多问题 我才八岁
I'm confused. I have questions. And I'm 8.
我现在想和妈妈谈谈
I want to talk to mommy now.
没问题 马克斯 妈妈马上就来
All right, Max, mommy's coming.
嘿 你们没事吧?你俩在那儿呆了好久了
Hey. You guys okay? You've been out here a long time.
马克斯和我还没聊完呢
Max and I have been hanging.
关于为什么有些问题这么复杂还有...
Talking about how all this has been confusing and how...
死亡怎么这么复杂
death is confusing.
不过他现在冷静多了
But he's calmer now.
我告诉他他今晚可以问我们
And I told him that tonight he can ask us
所有他有疑惑的问题
anything he wants to about all of this,
而我们会尽量告诉他真相 即使真相会很忧伤
and that we would try to answer truthfully, even if it's sad.
这样的话你就会好多了 小伙子?
Yeah? That make you feel better, kiddo?
对
Yeah.
好 那我们干嘛不去里面聊
Okay, so why don't you head on inside,
你躺在床上
you get ready for bed,
我们去找你 然后我们深入探讨一下死亡的话题
and then we'll come in and we'll have a nice, long conversation about death,
然后你就可以进入梦乡了
and then it's off to dream land.
- 待会儿见 - 当心点
- See you in there, buddy. - Just be careful. Okay.
好了 准备好了吗?数三下 一 二 三!
All right. Ready? On 3. 1, 2, 3!
亲娘咧!
Oopsie-daisy!
你没事吧?
You okay?
马蒂 我不喜欢你每天都吃芝士汉堡
Marty, I don't like that you eat cheeseburgers every day,
也不喜欢你拿你的哨子心开玩笑
and that you make jokes about your whistling heart.
我不想让你变成胡安那样
I don't want you to end up like Juan
不管是拉里动手前还是动手后的那种
before Larry got to him... or after, for that matter.
好啦 听我说好吗?
All right, listen to me, okay?
你一定要记得
There's something that you need to know.
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
除非是海豹突击队
It would take a team of navy S.E.A.L.S.
带着一队海豹亲自来
with a team of real seals
才可能把我从你和孩子们身边拖走
to drag me away from you and the kids.
明白吗?
Okay?
好 不过答应我以后偶尔吃点沙拉什么的
Okay. But promise me you'll try to eat a salad every once in a while,
或者和我一起去慢跑
and maybe you'll jog with me.
我以我的哨子心起誓
I cross my whistling heart.
好吧 这样说不好笑 我以后不会再说了
Okay, that's not even funny. I'gonna stop saying that.
最后一次了 好吧
Last time. Okay.
你还好吧?
You okay?
自从你把胡安安顿好后就一直坐在这儿了
You've been out here ever since you put Juan in the shed for the night.
我没事
I'm fine.
那就好
Okay.
我理解你
You know, I get you.
今天这么离奇 不过以后也许会变成好事
I mean, sometimes the best thing you can do after a crazy day like this
就这样坐在路边
is just sit on the curb
让黑夜洗去一切
and let the night wash over you.
马蒂 我不知道如果你...
Marty, I don't know if you...
只是...
It's just...
我以前可以解决各种问题
I've always been able to solve any problem.
在我们来这里之前
And we were prepared for some uncertainty
我们对未知尽量做了些准备
when we came to this planet.
我的孩子还不怎么了解这个世界
And my children really don't know this world.
而且...
And...
如果杰西和我出了什么事...
if anything should happen to Jackie and me...
虽然这只是也许 可是作为父亲...
Not that it can or will, but as a father, it...
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
会有人照顾你的孩子们的
Your children will be taken care of.
好了吗?
Okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
不过你也得考虑到
You should probably know that
万一你 我 黛比 还有杰西出了什么事...
if anything happens to you and Debbie, Jackie and I...
还有我妹妹呢
My sister's on it.
所以没问题的
So it's okay.
不过还是谢谢你关心 谢谢
But thank you. Thanks.
好了好了 时候到了
Okeydokey, it's time.
嘿 老兄 时间差不多了
So, uh, hey, buddy. It's time.
出发去新不伦瑞克了
Huh? Off to New Brunswick.
我想你表弟看到你一定会大吃一惊
I think your cousin's gonna be pretty surprised to see you.
你钱带够了吗?
You got enough, uh, cash to last?
我知道拉里一向慷慨
I know that Larry was very generous.
好吧 你该走了
Okay. Here you go.
我羡慕你即将面对的冒险
I envy you the adventure that awaits you,
胡安・萨尔加多
Juan Salgado.
多保重 好好享受这个世界
Be good. Enjoy the world.
记住 这种事我只能做一次
Remember, I was only able to do this once.
不要让我失望
Earn it.
好了好了
All right. Okay. All right.
让他走吧 他得走了 好了
Let him go now. He's gotta go. Okay.
马蒂 有关你孩子的监护权
Marty, about the guardianship of your children...
排在我们前面的有多少人?
How many people are ahead of us?
除非我们认识的所有人都死了你才有可能
Pretty much everyone we know would have to die.
也就是说我们还有机会了?
Oh, so we have a chance?
外
星
邻
居